# MICHAEL TODD

■ 46617 STONEHELM COURT, STERLING, VIRGINIA 20165 ① 713.539.8109 

MICHAELBTODD@YAHOO.COM

## 3D ARCHITECTURAL VISUALIZER / ANIMATOR

## QUALIFICATIONS PROFILE

Highly creative, concept-to-execution driven, and innovative professional with extensive experience in overseeing and executing the overall production of construction design and 3D and 2D illustration models in alignment with program requirements, budget, and time constraints. Armed with exceptional problem-solving, management, analytical, organizational, and communication skills, essential in achieving and surpassing company goals.

# AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Project and Program Development 3D Fly-Through and Animation creation Virtual Reality and 4d experience Photorealistic Architectural Renderings Contract Negotiation and Administration Cross-functional Leadership and Collaboration

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

STANTEC - HOUSTON, TX

## Designer | 3D Architectural Visualizer

2013-Present

- Utilize various technology tools in creating construction designs and models.
- Create environments and animations for client presentations and marketing.
- Advance working drawings to higher level of completion for Construction Document submissions.
- Work with multiple offices nationwide to create 3d models and photorealistic renderings for client and marketing presentations.

#### **Recent Career Highlight:**

→ 2016- Published in the Washington Post with renderings of the Academies of Loudoun County High School. Positioned the company for growth in successfully marketing to and serving dealing various clients, including Texas A&M College of Veterinary Medicine; HS#3, Katy STEM, Texas A&M Small Animal Clinic; and Houston Independent School District, the 4th largest district in the country with the largest school construction bond to date.

BAY ARCHITECTS - HOUSTON, TX

# 3D Architectural Visualizer | Animator

2010-2013

- Performed photorealistic texturing and rendering, as well as 2D illustration and Design.
- Advanced working drawings to higher level of completion for Construction Document submissions.

#### **Career Highlights:**

- → Boosted business efficiency in managing multiple visualization projects which include the following:
  - Channelview Independent School District;
  - Katy Independent School District;
  - Klein Independent School District;
  - New Caney Independent School District;
  - Pasadena Independent School District;
  - San Jacinto Community College; and
  - Texas Independent School District.

# MICHAEL TODD

# ■ 46617 STONEHELM COURT, STERLING, VIRGINIA 20165 ① 713.539.8109 MICHAELBTODD@YAHOO.COM

#### KIRKSEY ARCHITECTS - HOUSTON, TX

## 3D Architectural Visualizer | Animator

2007-2010

 Developed 3D architectural models of residential and commercial interiors, exteriors, and landscaping through 3ds Max and Vray.

# MUZE 3D – AVENTURA, FL; HOUSTON, TX

#### Freelance | 3D Illustrator and Animator

2006-2007

- Demonstrated creativity in formulating photorealistic architectural renderings and animations for drawing set presentation, websites, and brochures.
- Capitalized on industry expertise in fulfilling the following:
  - Architectural visualization from drawings and sketches;
  - Animations- fly-through and motion-capture character design; 3D Floorplans and sections
  - Photomontages in composting proposed improvements over existing photographs.

### EARLIER CAREER

ARQUITECTONICA – MIAMI, FL

Architect, Internship IV 2004–2006

JACKSON & RYAN ARCHITECTS - HOUSTON, TX

Architect, Internship III 2001–2004

## **EDUCATION**

### **Master of Architecture**

University of Houston, Gerald D. Hines College of Architecture

# Bachelor of Science in Biology, Minor in Chemistry

Texas Southern University – Houston, TX

## PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Unreal Engine 4.0
Coding Language Python | Amazon Web Service (AWS)

### **ACTIVITIES**

DC Area Virtual Reality Group

## **TECHNICAL ACUMEN**

3dsMax | Vray | Revit
Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, After Effects, Premiere, Lightroom, Illustrator, and Indesign)
Lumion | Unreal Engine | Sketchup | AutoCAD